Anthony Deamer

66 Daphne Street, Grange, QLD 4051 | 0437 373 450 | Anthony.Deamer@hotmail.com

Git-Hub: https://github.com/Adeamer

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anthony-deamer-13b3b3175/

Career Objective

To expand my knowledge and experience in the software and wed development industry. I have worked in the trade and logistics industry for the last 7 years. Throughout that time I gained a lot of experience with working with computers and creating strong connections with cliental.

Education

YEAR 12 CERTIFICATE | 1999 | ALBANY CREEK STATE HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA OF INTERNATIONAL FREIGHT FORWARDING | 2016 | CBFCA CODING BOOTCAMP | 2021 | UNIVERSITY OF ADELAIDE- CURRENT

Skills & Abilities

COMPUTERS

- · Microsoft Office Excel, Word, Outlook
- · Airline Operating System HERMIES
- · Milman Operating System
- · Cyber Freight
- · Git-Hub
- · Visual Studio Code
- · Git Bash
- · HTML
- · CSS
- Javascript
- · NodeIS
- · Bootstrap
- · Jquery
- · Moment.JS
- · Bulma.io
- Express
- · Sequelize

- · MYSQL
- Bootstrap
- · Heroku

COMMUNICATION

• It has been a requirement of all of the positions I have held to have excellent communication skills as well as building and maintaining good working relationships with suppliers, customers and colleagues

MANAGEMENT

• Whilst working with Toll Dnata I covered the team leader's position on a number of occasions. Motivating team members to consistently exceed expectation. There were from 5 to 10 people under me at one time per shift. As well as training staff and monitoring their progress at Wallace International.

RECENT PROJECT & WORK

- Professional Portfolio- This was 1 of the first piece of homework given in the bootcamp, I
 enjoyed this because it allowed me to be creative for my own benefit. As this was earlier on this
 only consists of HTML and CSS. Here is a link to my deployed application:
 https://adeamer.github.io/Week-2-homework/
- News/Media Aggregator- This was the first group project, I was nervous at first to work with a group as I was used to working solo. But soon realized the benefits of working in a group. The project is a aggregator application that brings together reddit post and articles from the Guardian news website. The language used in this application was HTML, Javascript Bulma CSS framework, Reddit API and The guardian API. The idea was to bring together these sites so the user can has one place to up to date news and reddit posts. Here is the link to the deployed application: https://adeamer.github.io/Week-7-Project/Index
- Weather Dashboard- This project I found the most difficult but at the same the most rewarding.
 This was because I would run into a problem, spent time researching how to fix it and find out
 why the problem was occurring. The language used in this application was HTML, CSS, Bulma
 CSS framework, Javascript and Jquery. Here is the link to the deployed application:
 https://adeamer.github.io/Week6-Weather-Dashboard/
- Your Plant House- This was the second group project that was to be completed in the boot camp course. For my group we brainstormed and our real life problem was to do with plants how plant owners can keep track of what they have and where they have them. The languages used were HTML, Javscript and CSS on the front end and for the back used JS, JSON and various NPM packages like express, express-sequelize, MYSQL2, Bycrpt, doteny, and connect-session sequelize. The big thing I learnt from this project was how much organization needs to be done in order for the work flow to run smoothly as I took on the organization role for my group. My group did run into quite a few errors that ended up us having to create a new Git-Hub repository as the original repository only had broken code in it. After all the problems me and my group were able to successfully create a full stack web application and have it deployed in Heroku.

Work History

IMPORT SEA/ RUNNER | WALLACE INTERNATIONAL | SEPTEMBER 2020 - CURRENT

Key Responsibilities included:

- Checking for documentation at each airline for inbound shipments.
- Registering shipments into the Cyber Freight system as operational jobs.
- Creating and confirming the correct charges on disbursement and final invoices for clients.
- Checking and updating transshipments and confirming of transshipment vessels.
- Communicating and booking inspections on behalf of particular clients with the Department of Agriculture and Water Resources.
- Lodging documents with quarantine.
- Paying out entries to get a clear status.
- Receiving ship spare parts and, organizing under-bond and deliveries to the Wharf.
- Booking cartage for Air freight, LCL and FCL shipments
- Keeping clients up to date with their shipments for deliveries.
- Quoting cartage for clients.
- Backing up every file/shipment onto a hard drive.
- Confirming with clients of correct documentation for entries.
- Communicating with different Freight Forwarders and Shipping lines for Arrival notices, Tax Invoices, Delivery Orders and Outturn Reports.

•

OPERATIONS CLERK - RUNNER | CUSTOMS AND FORWARDING SERVICES | OCTOBER 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2020

Key Responsibilities included:

- Checking for documentation at each airline for inbound shipments.
- Registering shipments into the Cyber Freight system as operational jobs.
- Creating and confirming the correct charges on disbursement and final invoices for clients.
- Checking and updating transshipments and confirming of transshipment vessels.
- Communicating and booking inspections on behalf of particular clients with the Department of Agriculture and Water Resources.
- Lodging documents with quarantine.
- Paying out entries to get a clear status.
- Receiving ship spare parts and, organizing under-bond and deliveries to the Wharf.
- Booking cartage for Air freight, LCL and FCL shipments
- Keeping clients up to date with their shipments for deliveries.
- Quoting cartage for clients.
- Backing up every file/shipment onto a hard drive.
- Confirming with clients of correct documentation for entries.
- Communicating with different Freight Forwarders and Shipping lines for Arrival notices, Tax Invoices, Delivery Orders and Outturn Reports.

BAGGAGE HANDLER - RAMP SERVICES AND AIR-CARGO AGENT | TOLL DNATA | JANUARY 2012 - JUNE 2014

Key Responsibilities included:

- · Supporting and covering the team leader position
- · Baggage handling
- Heavy machinery operations
- · Two way radio operation
- · Processing cargo documents
- · Operating the Hermies Airline computer system which included data capturing all of the Air Way Bills (AWB); requesting under-bonds for cargo; checking fees and correcting if necessary; creating flights for unexpected inbound flights; preparing inbound flights to be ready for when flights arrived and receiving inbound documents in the system.
- · Ensure cargo had customs clearance
- · Operating the Emerites Sky Cargo computer system print AWB's for inbound flights
- · Data entry on the Virgin Australia WABlink computer system. This was to ensure that the load control would be able to load the plan safely
- · General Customer service
- · Receiving import and export cargo
- · Follow company policies and procedures to ensure safe work practice

SALES ASSISTANT | HARRY BROWNS LIQUOR STORE | DECEMBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2012

Key Responsibilities included:

- · Customer Service
- Support management by restocking merchandise and maintaining excellent customer service standards
- · Managed cash register credit card, cash and return transactions ensuring register balanced.
- · Monthly Stock take
- · Manual handling

SIGN WRITER ASSISTANT | PLANET WRAP SIGN WRITING | JANUARY 2010 - DECEMBER 2010

Key Responsibilities included:

- · Customer Service
- · Assisting with the design, making, painting and installation of signs for a variety of customers
- Ensure that work was completed to tight deadlines
- · Working and learning practical skills on the job

REFEREES

David Gray – Operations Customs and Forwarding Services Mobile -0424 505 435

Wayne Anderson- Office Team Leader Toll Dnata Cargo Service Mobile: 0420 505103

Additional references available on request.